DELOWAR HOSSAIN

PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Vue, Tailwind CSS Secondary Stack: React, Shopify, WordPress, Codelgniter

My Contact

- contact.delowar@gmail.com
- (+880-182-450-2831
- North Kattali, Akbar Shah, Chattogram
- https://delowar.me
- github.com/illusionist3886
- nackerrank.com/illusionist3886

Hard Skills

- PHP
- · Laravel, Codelgniter
- JavaScript, jQuery
- Vue, React
- CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS
- Shopify, Liquid, WordPress
- MySQL, GraphQL
- Automation (Bash)
- Server Management
- OSINT

Soft Skills

- Leadership
- Observation
- · Decision making
- Deep Analysis
- Teamwork

Education Background

- Masters of Business Administration
 Major in Supply Chain Management
 University of Chittagong
- Bachelor of Business Administration
 University of Chittagong
- Higher Secondary School Certificate
 Science Group
 Govt. City College, Chittagong.

About Me

I am a full-stack developer with extensive experience building ERP systems for industries like container shipping, healthcare, ISP, and bulk carriers. I specialize in frontend and backend development using Laravel, Vue, and a little React, with skills in API development, IoT integration, and server deployment automation. I've also handled payment gateway integration and WebSocket for push notifications.

In addition to development, I have strong **cybersecurity** expertise, reporting vulnerabilities and securing corporate systems. I contribute to opensource projects and have developed **android apps** and **chrome extensions** for the **Muslim** community. My **reverse engineering** work focuses on data extraction and application security.

Professional Experience - Full Time

Magnetism Tech Limited | Senior Full Stack Developer September 2021 - Present

Contributions:

- Container Shipping ERP
 - EDI Parser
 - RESTful APIs and Vue Frontend
 - Server Deployment Automation Git Hook.
- Bulk Carrier ERP
 - RESTful APIs and Vue Frontend
- ISP ERP
 - Full Stack Development (Laravel and Blade)
 - WebSocket Implementation for Push Notification.
- Health Care Service Provider
 - Doctor Booking System
 - Online Video Calling (Twilio SDK)
 - Hospital Management
- Fuel Filling ERP
 - RESTful APIs and Vue Frontend
 - Integration with IoT Device to monitor fuel inventory.
- Garments ERP
 - Vue Frontend

Contribution to Muslim

Ruqyah App Development (Android - Adobe Cordoba)

Ash Shifa. (Database Part)

Chrome Extension

Muslim's Day - Data

OSS Contributions

Laravel

Laravel Modules

OWASP Amass (Pending)

Cyber Security

- Reported Brute Force Account Takeover Vulnerability, SQLi, XSS on a PHP Application. (Freelance).
- Forensics and Recovered Hacked Airport Website (CrystalAirOnline)
- Secured Wi-Fi Infrastructure in a corporate office. (NDA)
- Protection Added to Website Against Brute Force, XSS and SQLi.

Reverse Engineering

- Android Application. (Database extraction with written permission of GTAF)
- Flutter Desktop Application. (Security Testing)
- Open SSH on CentOS Machine. (Security through obfuscation)

Server Management

- Experience with Debian and Red Hat Distros. (Ubuntu, CentOS, AlmaLinux and Rocky Linux)
- cPanel and Cyber Panel.
- Automatic DB Backup and Clean through bash and cronjob.
- Laravel Schedule through supervisor.

EasyFie | Lead Frontend Developer

January 2021 - August 2021

Contributions:

 Templating for E-Commerce, Portfolio, Blog, Job Posting and Social Networking Application.

Isratts Technology | Full Stack Developer

September 2020 - January 2021

Contributions:

- Hospital ERP
 - Full Stack Development. (Laravel, Blade and a little of Vue)
- ERP for Machinery Trading Company
 - Full Stack Development. (Laravel and Blade)

Professional Experience - Contractual

Websites and Web Applications

- Image Based Authentication System
- Health Care Portal (e-healthbd.com)
- Pilot Payroll System (Crystal Air Inc.)
- Care Home Activities System (Magic Moments Activities)
- E-Commerce (Multiple)
- Hall Booking System
- Marriage Media (El-7l, Egypt)
- Numerous Performance Boost and Bug Fixing
- POS for Feni E-mart Super Shop
- Print on Demand Web Application (Konva.js)

Other Stacks I Worked On

- WordPress
 - Theme Customization
 - Plugin Development
 - Performance Boosting
- Shopify
 - Embedded App Development
 - Liquid
 - GraphQL
 - Webhook implementation to track shop's data remotely
- Codelgniter
 - Web Portal Development
 - Web Based Games Modification
- Node.js
 - Web Scraping through Proxy Chaining.

Certifications and Achievements

Pentester Lab, Web Application Security

BASIS, BITM Web Design Course